<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./parquetwriter-icon.png" type="Sink" 
xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>Parquet Writer</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Writes KNIME tables into a Parquet File
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node writes the KNIME data table into a Parquet file. The Parquet file can be written locally or on a remote file system.
        <p>
        For remote connections, the writer stores chunks locally and uploads them in parallel into a folder with the given name. 
        The chunks size and the number of chunks that are allowed on local disc, are configurable in the "Chunk Upload" 
        tab which is only enabled for remote file systems.
        </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
       	 <option name="Output location">A path on the local machine or remote server where the file is written.</option>
       	 <option name="Overwrite">If this option is selected the file will be overwritten if it exists</option>
       	 <option name="Check directory content">Enabled when using a remote connection and enabling the overwrite option. 
       	 With this option enabled the node will fail if the content of the directory contains files that do not fit the file format suffix</option>
       	 <option name="File Compression">The compression codec used to write the Parquet file.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Chunk Upload">
      	  <option name="Chunk size in MB">The maximum size for an individual chunk.</option>
      	  <option name="Number of local chunks">The number of chunks that can be stored temporarily on disc, while the next chunk is written.</option>
    	</tab>
    	<tab name="Output Type Mapping">
    	   <description>
	            Change the KNIME to Parquet type mapping configuration
	            for subsequent nodes by selecting a Parquet type to the given
	            KNIME Type.
	            The dialog allows you to add new or change existing type mapping rules.
            </description>
	         <option name="Mapping by Name">
	            Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and KNIME type will be mapped
	            to the specified Parquet type.
	         </option>
	         <option name="Mapping by Type">
	            Columns that match the given KNIME type will be mapped to the specified Parquet type.
	         </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Remote connection">An optional connection to the remote file system </inPort>   
        <inPort index="1" name="Data">The data table that should be written</inPort>        
    </ports>    

</knimeNode>
