<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10" type="Manipulator" icon="icon.png">
    <name>Spark Partitioning</name>
    <shortDescription>Splits input data into two partitions.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
       <intro>
            The input data is split into two partitions (i.e. row-wise),
            e.g. train and test data. The two partitions are available at the
            two output ports. The following options are available in the dialog:
        </intro>
        <option name="Absolute">
            Specify the absolute number of rows in the sample. If there are less rows than specified here, all rows are
            used.
        </option>
        <option name="Relative">
            The percentage of the number of rows in the sample. Must be between 0 and 100, inclusively.
        </option>
        <option name="Take from top">This mode selects the top most rows of the input data.</option>
        <option name="Draw randomly">
            Random sampling of all rows, you may optionally specify a fixed seed (see below).
        </option>
        <option name="Stratified sampling">
            Check this button if you want 
            <a href="https://spark.apache.org/docs/1.2.0/mllib-statistics.html#stratified-sampling">stratified sampling</a>, 
            i.e. the distribution of values in the selected column is (approximately) retained in the output table. 
            You may optionally specify a fixed seed (see below). 
        </option>
        <option name="Exact sampling">
            Exact sampling requires significant more resources than the per-stratum simple random sampling used in 
            by default, but will provide the exact sampling size with 99.99% confidence. 
        </option>
        <option name="Use random seed">
            If either random or stratified sampling is selected, you may enter a fixed seed here
            in order to get reproducible results upon re-execution. If you do not specify a seed,
            a new random seed is taken for each execution. 
        </option>
        <option name="Sample with replacement">
            If selected a row from the input data can be chosen more than once. 
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Spark RDD">Spark RDD to take the sample from.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="First partition (as defined in dialog)">
            First partition (as defined in dialog).</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Second partition (remaining rows)">
            Second partition (remaining rows).</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
