<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd"
    type="Learner" icon="icon.png">
  <name>Spark Association Rule Learner</name>
  <shortDescription>Find frequent item sets and learn association rules in Spark.</shortDescription>
  <fullDescription>
    <intro>
      <p>
        This rule learner* uses Spark MLlib to compute frequent item sets and then extract association rules from the given input data. 
        Association rules describe relations between items in a set of transactions. For example, if a customer bought <i>onions,
        potatos</i> and <i>meat</i> in a transaction, this implies that a new customer who buys <i>onions</i> and <i>potatos</i> is likely
        to also buy <i>meat</i>. This can be written as an association rule with <i>onions</i> and <i>potatos</i> as antecedents and
        <i>meat</i> as consequent.
      </p>

      <p>
        Transactions/item sets are represented as collection columns. The <i>Spark GroupBy</i> or <i>Spark SQL</i> nodes are
        recommended to create collection columns in Spark.
      </p>

      <p>
        Frequent item sets are computed using the <a href="https://spark.apache.org/docs/2.2.0/mllib-frequent-pattern-mining.html">FP-growth</a>
        implementation provided by Spark MLlib, using input data with a collection column, where each cell holds the items of a transaction.
        Rows with <i>missing values</i> in the selected item column are <i>ignored</i>. 
        FP-growth uses a suffix tree (FP-tree) structure to encode transactions without generating candidate sets explicitly and then extracts
        the frequent item sets from this FP-tree. This approach avoids the usually expensive generation of explicit candidates sets used in
        Apriori-like algorithms designed for the same purpose. More information about the FP-Growth algorithm can be found in
        <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/335191.335372">Han et al., Mining frequent patterns without candidate generation</a>.
        Spark implements <i>Parallel FP-growth (PFP)</i> described in <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/1454008.1454027">Li
        et al., PFP: Parallel FP-Growth for Query Recommendation</a>.
      </p>

      <p>
        <a href="https://spark.apache.org/docs/2.2.0/mllib-frequent-pattern-mining.html#association-rules">Association rules</a> are computed using Spark MLlib,
        using the previously computed frequent item sets. Each association rule maps an item set (<i>antecedent</i>) to a single item (<i>consequent</i>).
        The <i>Spark Association Rule Apply</i> node can be used to apply the rules produced by this node.
      </p>

      <p>
        See <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Association_rule_learning">Association rule learning (Wikipedia)</a> for general information.
      </p>

      <p><i>This node requires at least Apache Spark 2.0.</i></p>
      <br/>
      (*) RULE LEARNER is a registered trademark of Minitab, LLC and is used with Minitab’s permission.
    </intro>

    <option name="Item Column">
      Collection column, where each cell holds the items of a transaction.
    </option>
    <option name="Minimum Support">
      The minimum support for an item set to be identified as frequent. For example, if an item set appears in 3 out of 5 transactions, it has a support of 3/5=0.6 (default: 0.3).
    </option>
    <option name="Number of partitions">
      Optional: Number of partitions used by the Parallel FP-growth algorithm to distribute the work (default: same as input data).
    </option>
    <option name="Minimum Confidence">
      Sets the minimum confidence for association rules (default: 0.8). Association rules are filtered based on <i>confidence</i>. 
      Confidence is an indication of how often an association rule has been found to be true.
      For example, if the item set A appears in 10 transactions, and item sets A and B co-occur one time, then the confidence for the rule A => B is 1/10 = 0.1.
    </option>
  </fullDescription>

  <ports>
    <inPort index="0" name="Spark data">Spark DataFrame  with a collection column, where each cell holds the items of a transaction</inPort>
    <outPort index="0" name="Association rules">Spark DataFrame with association rules</outPort>
    <outPort index="1" name="Frequent item sets">Spark DataFrame with frequent item sets</outPort>
  </ports>
</knimeNode>
