<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.12" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.12 http://knime.org/node/v2.12.xsd"
    type="Manipulator" icon="icon.png">

	<name>Spark PCA</name>
	<shortDescription>Principal component analysis (PCA) in Spark.</shortDescription>
  <fullDescription>
    <intro>
      This node performs a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Principal_component_analysis">
      principal component analysis (PCA)</a> on the given data using the Apache Spark
      <a href="http://spark.apache.org/docs/latest/ml-features.html#pca">implementation</a>.
      The input data is projected from its original feature space into a space of (possibly) lower
      dimension with a minimum of information loss.
    </intro>
    <option name="Fail if missing values are encountered">
      If checked, execution fails, when the selected columns contain missing values.
      By default, rows containing missing values are ignored and not considered in the computation of the principal components.
    </option>
	<option name="Target dimensions">
		Select the number of dimensions the input data is projected to. You
		can select either one of:
		<ul>
			<li>
				<i>Dimensions to reduce to:</i>
				Directly specify the number of target dimensions. The specified
				number must be lower or equal than the number of input columns.
			</li>
			<li>
				<i>Minimum information fraction to preserve (%):</i>
				Specify the fraction in percentage of information to preserve from
				the input columns. This option requires Apache Spark 2.0 or
				higher.
			</li>
		</ul>
	</option>
	<option name="Replace original data columns">
		If checked, the projected DataFrame/RDD will not contain columns that
		were included in the principal component analysis. Only the projected
		columns and the input columns that were <i>not</i> included in the
		principal component analysis remain.
	</option>
    <option name="Columns">
      Select columns that are included in the analysis of principal components, i.e the original features.
    </option>
  </fullDescription>

  <ports>
    <inPort index="0" name="Spark DataFrame/RDD">Input Spark DataFrame/RDD</inPort>
    <outPort index="0" name="Projected Input DataFrame/RDD">
    	The input DataFrame/RDD projected onto the principal components. Input
    	columns that were <i>not</i> included in the principal component
    	analysis are retained.</outPort>
    <outPort index="1" name="Principal Component Matrix">A DataFrame/RDD with the principal components matrix.</outPort>
  </ports>
</knimeNode>
