<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="org.knime.features.bigdata.commons.windows"
      label="KNIME Extension for Big Data Commons on Windows"
      version="4.3.0.qualifier"
      provider-name="KNIME AG, Zurich, Switzerland">

   <description>
     Features require by Big Data Commons extension on Windows.
   </description>

   <license url="">
Terms for License of Microsoft Redistributable Feature
0. General
===========
This feature and the contained MICROSOFT REDISTRIBUTABLE SOFTWARE PACKAGE ("Software") is provided to you by KNIME AG ("KNIME") on this special license. 
The Software is the intellectual property of Microsoft Corporation or its licensors. KNIME licenses the Software to you under these terms and conditions. You can obtain the Software also from Microsoft's servers under Microsoft Software License Terms.
The Software is protected by law, including without limitation copyright laws and international treaty provisions. Except for the rights explicitly granted to you in this License Agreement, all right, title and interest in the Software are reserved. You do not acquire any intellectual property or other rights in the Software as a result of downloading the Software.

1. Use of the Software; Distribution
=====================================
KNIME hereby grants you a personal, limited, non-exclusive, non-transferable, non-sublicenseable license to install and use the feature including the Software. 

2. Limitations
===============
You may not use the Software for any illegal purpose. You may not, and you will not encourage, assist or authorize any other person to, (a) sell, rent, lease, lend, loan, copy, distribute, act as a service bureau, publicly communicate, transform, or sub-license the Software or otherwise assign any rights to the Software in whole or in part; (b) modify, alter, tamper with, repair, or otherwise create derivative works of the Software, (c) reverse engineer, disassemble, or decompile the Software or apply any other process or procedure to derive the source code of any software included in the Software, (d) work around any technical limitations in the Software (e) publish the Software for others to copy, (f) use the Software for commercial software hosting services, or (g) access or use the Software in a way intended to avoid incurring fees or exceeding usage limits or quotas.

3. Disclaimer of Warranties and Limitation of Liability
========================================================
a. YOU EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT INSTALLATION AND USE OF, AND ANY OTHER ACCESS TO, THE SOFTWARE IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK. THE SOFTWARE IS DELIVERED TO YOU "AS IS" WITH ALL FAULTS AND WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, AND KNIME DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, ACCURACY, QUIET ENJOYMENT, AND NON-INFRINGEMENT. NO ORAL OR WRITTEN INFORMATION OR ADVICE GIVEN BY KNIME OR AN AUTHORIZED REPRESENTATIVE OF KNIME WILL CREATE A WARRANTY. 

b. TO THE EXTENT NOT PROHIBITED BY LAW, KNIME WILL NOT BE LIABLE TO YOU FOR ANY INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES FOR BREACH OF ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY, BREACH OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE, STRICT LIABILITY, OR ANY OTHER LEGAL THEORY RELATED TO THE SOFTWARE, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION ANY DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF LOSS OF PROFITS, REVENUE, DATA, OR USE OF THE SOFTWARE, EVEN IF KNIME HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. IN ANY CASE, KNIME'S AGGREGATE LIABILITY UNDER THIS LICENSE AGREEMENT WILL BE LIMITED TO $25.00.

4. Miscellaneous
=================
This feature and the library is licensed to you, not sold. With this license agreement you receive a license for the Software from KNIME. Microsoft and others are the owner of the Software, but KNIME and Microsoft are not in any way through this agreement in any kind of partnership, joint venture, or any other relationship - and nothing in this agreement implies this. KNIME is no representative or agent of Microsoft and has no authority to enter into any agreement on Microsoft's behalf or on Microsoft's name or otherwise bind Microsoft to any agreement or obligation.

5. Export Restrictions
=======================
The feature and the Software is subject to United States export laws and regulations. You must comply with all domestic and international export laws and regulations that apply to the feature and the Software. These laws include restrictions on destinations, end users and end use. For additional information, see www.microsoft.com/exporting
   </license>

   <plugin
         id="org.knime.bigdata.commons.windows"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         fragment="true"/>

</feature>
