<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="icon.png" type="Source" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.12" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.12 http://knime.org/node/v2.12.xsd">
    <name>Create Spark Context</name>
    
    <shortDescription>Creates a new Spark context.</shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Creates a new Spark Context. The settings e.g. dispose on reset affect all connected Spark nodes and 
            their successors.
            <p>The default values of the node are taken from the Spark preference page which
            you can open via <i>File->Preferences->KNIME->Spark</i>.</p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Context Settings">
        <option name="Spark version">
        	The Spark version the Job Server is working with.
        </option>
        <option name="Context name">The unique name of the context.</option>
        <option name="Delete Spark context on dispose">If selected KNIME deletes the Spark context when the workflow or
        KNIME is closed. This way resources on the Spark job server are released but ALL nodes have to be re-executed
        the next time the workflow is opened.</option>
        <option name="Delete Spark objects on dispose">If selected KNIME deletes the created Spark objects e.g. 
        DataFrames/RDDs when the workflow or KNIME is closed. This way resources within the corresponding Spark context 
        are released but ALL nodes have to be re-executed the next time the workflow is opened.</option>
        <option name="Spark job log level">The log level to use for Spark jobs within the Spark runtime.</option>
        <option name="Override spark settings">Select this option to enable user specific Spark context settings.</option>
        <option name="Custom spark settings">Custom settings to use in addition or to overwrite the default context settings defined in the Spark Job Server.</option>
        <option name="Hide context exists warning">Enable this option to suppress context exists warning messages.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Connection Settings">
        <option name="Job server URL">The URL of the Spark job server including protocol and port e.g. http://localhost:8090.</option>
        <option name="Authentication">Either none  or user name and password which is required if authentication is enabled in the Spark job server.</option>
        <option name="Job server receive timeout (seconds)">Time to wait on a Spark job server REST request for a response (0 is infinite).</option>
        <option name="Spark job check frequency (seconds)">The frequency KNIME has to check the job status.</option>        
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Spark context">Spark context.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
