<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="impala_connector.png"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>Impala Connector</name>
    <shortDescription>Create a database connection to Impala.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node creates a connection to a Impala server via its JDBC
            driver. You need to provide the server's
            hostname
            (or IP address), the port, and a database name. Login credentials can
            either be provided directly in
            the configuration or via credentials set on the workflow.
        </intro>
        <tab name="Connection settings">
            <option name="Database Dialect">
                Choose the registered database dialect here.
            </option>
            <option name="Driver Name">
                Choose the registered database driver here.
                Additional drivers can be registered via KNIME's preference 
                page "KNIME -> Databases".
                <br/>
                The node supports the usage of the Apache Hive drivers (already included in KNIME) and
                Cloudera JDBC drivers which are available for download from the
                <a href="http://www.cloudera.com/downloads/connectors/impala/jdbc.html">Cloudera homepage</a>.
            </option>
            <option name="Hostname">
                The hostname (or IP address) of a Impala server.
            </option>
            <option name="Port">
                The port on which the Impala server is listening. The default port
                is 21,050.
            </option>
            <option name="Database name">
                The name of the database you want to connect to.
            </option>
            <option name="None">
                If checked, the authentication is not required.
            </option>
            <option name="Credentials">
                If checked, the credentials (user and password) are used as defined on
                the workflow. The credential name
                links to the specified user and password. Those can be replaced or edited
                the 'Workflow Credentials'
                menu available in the workflow's context menu.
            </option>
            <option name="Username">
                Your log-in user name for the database.
            </option>
            <option name="Username &amp; password">
                Your log-in user name and password for the database. Note that the password 
                is encrypted before storage and decrypted afterwards for being used internally.
            </option>
            <option name="Use Kerberos">
            Uses an existing Kerberos ticket for authentication. When connecting to Impala the principal of the 
            Impala user needs to be added in the Parameter tab e.g. <i>principal=impala/impala_host@YOUR-REALM.COM</i>.
            The principal must be the same user principal you used when starting the Impala Server. For details see the 
            <a href="https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/Hive/HiveServer2+Clients#HiveServer2Clients-JDBCClientSetupforaSecureCluster">Hive documentation</a>
            or the <a href="http://www.cloudera.com/documentation/other/connectors/hive-jdbc/latest/Cloudera-JDBC-Driver-for-Apache-Impala-Install-Guide.pdf">Cloudera JDBC Driver for Apache Impala Install Guide</a>.
       		</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="JDBC Parameters">
            <description>
                This tab allows you define JDBC driver connection parameter. The value of a parameter can be a 
                constant, variable, credential user, credential password or KNIME URL.
                For more information about the supported driver properties see the 
                <a href="https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/Hive/HiveServer2+Clients#HiveServer2Clients-ConnectionURLs">Hive documentation</a>
                or the <a href="http://www.cloudera.com/documentation/other/connectors/hive-jdbc/latest/Cloudera-JDBC-Driver-for-Apache-Impala-Install-Guide.pdf">Cloudera JDBC Driver for Apache Impala Install Guide</a>.
             </description>
            <option name=""></option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define KNIME framework properties such as connection handling,
                advanced SQL dialect settings or logging options.
            </description>
            <option name=""></option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Input Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from database types to KNIME types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and database type will be mapped
                to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given database type will be mapped to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Output Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from KNIME types to database types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and KNIME type will be mapped
                to the specified database type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given KNIME type will be mapped to the specified database type.
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Database Connection">A database connection</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
