<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="impala_connector.png"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Impala Connector</name>
    <shortDescription>Create a database connection to Apache Impala™.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node creates a connection to Apache Impala™ via JDBC. You need to provide the server
            hostname (or IP address), the port, and a database name and specify an authentication mechanism.
            <p>
            This node uses the selected driver's 
            <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html#url_template">JDBC URL template</a> 
            to create the concrete database URL. Field validation in the dialog depends on whether the (included) 
            tokens referencing them are mandatory or optional in the template.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Connection settings">
            <option name="Database Dialect">
                Choose the registered database dialect here.
            </option>
            <option name="Database Driver">
                <p>
                Choose the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JDBC_driver">JDBC driver</a> to connect to the 
                database here. If you select "Use latest driver version available" upon execution the node will 
                automatically use the driver with the latest (highest) driver version that is available for the 
                current database type. This has the advantage that you do not need to touch the workflow after a 
                driver update. However, the workflow might break in the rare case that the behavior of the driver 
                e.g. type mapping changes with the newer version.
                </p>
                <p>
                If this option is not enabled, you can select a specific version of the registered drivers via the 
                drop-down list. Additional drivers can be registered via KNIME's preference 
                page "KNIME -> Databases". For more details on how to register a new driver see the
                <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html#register_jdbc">database documentation</a>.
                </p>
                <p>
                The node includes the Apache Hive driver, which is compatible with Impala.
                Proprietary drivers are also supported, but need to be registered first, such as the 
                <a href="http://www.cloudera.com/downloads/connectors/impala/jdbc.html">
                Impala JDBC connector</a> provided by Cloudera.
                </p>       
            </option>
            <option name="Hostname">
                The hostname (or IP address) of a Impala server. The corresponding driver URL template variable is
                <tt>host</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="Port">
                The port on which the Impala server is listening. The default port is 21,050. The corresponding driver
                URL template variable is <tt>port</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="Database name">
                The name of the database you want to connect to. The corresponding driver URL template variable is
                <tt>database</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="None">
                If checked, then authentication is not required.
            </option>
            <option name="Credentials">
                If checked, the credentials (user and password) are used as defined in the workflow. The credential name
                links to the specified user and password. 
            </option>
            <option name="Username">
                Your username for the database.
            </option>
            <option name="Username &amp; password">
                Your username and password for the database. Note that the password is stored using weak
                encryption as part the workflow .
            </option>
            <option name="Kerberos">
	            Uses an existing Kerberos ticket for authentication. Note that this requires additional
	            parameters to be specified in the <i>JDBC Parameters</i> tab (see below).
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="JDBC Parameters">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define <b>driver-specific</b> parameters for the JDBC connection. The
                value of a parameter can be a constant, variable, credential user, credential password or KNIME URL.
                For more information about the parameters supported by the included Apache Hive driver, please consult
                the 
                <a href="https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/Hive/HiveServer2+Clients#HiveServer2Clients-ConnectionURLs">Hive documentation</a>.
                When using a proprietary Hive driver, please consult the vendor documentation, e.g.
                <a href="https://www.cloudera.com/documentation/other/connectors/impala-jdbc/latest/Cloudera-JDBC-Driver-for-Impala-Install-Guide.pdf">Cloudera JDBC Driver for Apache Impala Install Guide</a>.
             </description>
            <option name="Kerberos">
            	The following parameters are required to use Kerberos authentication. 
            	<p>
            		<b>Apache Hive Driver (default KNIME driver)</b>
            		<ul>
            			<li>kerberosAuthType: fromSubject</li>
            			<li>principal: hive/&lt;server&gt;@&lt;REALM&gt; (replace &lt;server&gt; with the fully qualified hostname
            			and &lt;REALM&gt; with the Kerberos realm of the Hive service).</li>
            		</ul>
            	</p>

            	<p>
            		<b>Proprietary Impala Drivers (provided by Amazon/Hortonworks/Cloudera)</b>
            		<ul>
            			<li>AuthMech: 1</li>
            			<li>KrbHostFQDN: full qualified hostname of Impala</li>
            			<li>KrbRealm: REALM (Kerberos realm of Impala)</li>
            			<li>KrbServiceName: impala (Kerberos service name of Impala)</li>
            		</ul>
            	</p>
            </option>
            <option name="SSL/TLS">
            	The following parameters are required to use SSL/TLS. 
            	<p>
            		<b>Apache Hive Driver (default KNIME driver)</b>
            		<ul>
            			<li>ssl: true</li>
            			<li>sslTrustStore: full path of truststore</li>
            			<li>trustStorePassword: password to access the truststore</li>
            		</ul>
            	</p>

            	<p>
            		<b>Proprietary Impala Drivers (provided by Amazon/Hortonworks/Cloudera)</b>
            		<ul>
            			<li>SSL: 1</li>
            			<li>SSLTrustStore: full path of truststore</li>
            			<li>SSLTrustStorePwd: password to access the truststore</li>
            		</ul>
            	</p>
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define KNIME framework properties such as connection handling,
                advanced SQL dialect settings or logging options.
            </description>
            <option name="Advanced Parameters">
                For more information about the supported parameters see the 
                <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/db_extension_guide/index.html#advanced_tab">KNIME Database Extension Guide.</a>
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Input Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from database types to KNIME types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and database type will be mapped
                to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given database type will be mapped to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Output Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from KNIME types to database types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and KNIME type will be mapped
                to the specified database type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given KNIME type will be mapped to the specified database type.
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Database Connection">A database connection</outPort>
    </ports>
    <keywords>
        <keyword>database</keyword>
        <keyword>db</keyword>
    </keywords>
</knimeNode>
