<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode type="Source" icon="impala_connector.png"
    xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>Impala Connector</name>
    <shortDescription>Create a database connection to Apache Impala™.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node creates a connection to Apache Impala™ via JDBC. You need to provide the server
            hostname (or IP address), the port, and a database name and specify an authentication mechanism.
            <hr/>
            <h3>Driver URL template:</h3>
            <p>This node uses the selected driver's URL template for creating the concrete database URL.
            For additional drivers, which are not provided by the KNIME database modules, the <i>URL template</i>
            is to be specified on the driver preferences page under KNIME/Databases. E.g.</p>
            <tt>jdbc:hive2://&lt;host&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/[database]</tt>
            <p>is a possible Impala driver URL template, when the Hive driver is used.</p>
            <h4>Tokens:</h4>
            <ul>
            <li><b>Mandatory value</b> (e.g. <tt>&lt;database&gt;</tt>)<b>:</b><br/>
            The referenced variable must have a non-blank value.
            The name between the brackets must be a valid variable name.
            Please refer to the variable descriptions below.</li>
            <li><b>Optional value</b> (e.g. <tt>[database]</tt>)<b>:</b><br/>
            The referenced variable may have a blank value.
            The name between the brackets must be a valid variable name.
            Please refer to the variable descriptions below.</li>
            </ul>
            <h4>Variables:</h4>
            <ul>
            <li><tt>host</tt>:<br/>
            The value of the <b>Hostname</b> field on the <b>Connection Settings</b> tab.</li>
            <li><tt>port</tt>:<br/>
            The value of the <b>Port</b> field on the <b>Connection Settings</b> tab.</li>
            <li><tt>database</tt>:<br/>
            The value of the <b>Database name</b> field on the <b>Connection Settings</b> tab.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Field validation in the dialog depends on whether the (included) tokens referencing them are mandatory or
            optional.</p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Connection settings">
            <option name="Database Dialect">
                Choose the registered database dialect here.
            </option>
            <option name="Driver Name">
                Choose the registered database driver here.
                Additional drivers can be registered via KNIME's preference 
                page "KNIME -> Databases".
                <br/>
                The node includes the Apache Hive driver, which is compatible with Impala.
                Proprietary drivers are also supported, but need to be registered first, such as the 
                <a href="http://www.cloudera.com/downloads/connectors/impala/jdbc.html">
                Impala JDBC connector</a> provided by Cloudera.
            </option>
            <option name="Hostname">
                The hostname (or IP address) of a Impala server. The corresponding driver URL template variable is
                <tt>host</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="Port">
                The port on which the Impala server is listening. The default port is 21,050. The corresponding driver
                URL template variable is <tt>port</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="Database name">
                The name of the database you want to connect to. The corresponding driver URL template variable is
                <tt>database</tt>.
            </option>
            <option name="None">
                If checked, then authentication is not required.
            </option>
            <option name="Credentials">
                If checked, the credentials (user and password) need to be provided as a credentials flow
                variable. Credentials flow variables can be created with the <i>Credentials Input</i>
                node or using the 'Workflow Credentials' option available in the context menu
                of the workflow.
            </option>
            <option name="Username">
                Your username for the database.
            </option>
            <option name="Username &amp; password">
                Your username and password for the database. Note that the password is stored using weak
                encryption as part the workflow .
            </option>
            <option name="Kerberos">
	            Uses an existing Kerberos ticket for authentication. Note that this requires additional
	            parameters to be specified in the <i>JDBC Parameters</i> tab (see below).
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="JDBC Parameters">
            <description>
                This tab allows you define <b>driver-specific</b> parameters for the JDBC connection. The
                value of a parameter can be a constant, variable, credential user, credential password or KNIME URL.
                For more information about the parameters supported by the included Apache Hive driver, please consult
                the 
                <a href="https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/Hive/HiveServer2+Clients#HiveServer2Clients-ConnectionURLs">Hive documentation</a>.
                When using a proprietary Hive driver, please consult the vendor documentation, e.g.
                <a href="https://www.cloudera.com/documentation/other/connectors/impala-jdbc/latest/Cloudera-JDBC-Driver-for-Impala-Install-Guide.pdf">Cloudera JDBC Driver for Apache Impala Install Guide</a>.
             </description>
            <option name="Kerberos">
            	The following parameters are required to use Kerberos authentication. 
            	<p>
            		<b>Apache Hive Driver (default KNIME driver)</b>
            		<ul>
            			<li>kerberosAuthType: fromSubject</li>
            			<li>principal: hive/&lt;server&gt;@&lt;REALM&gt; (replace &lt;server&gt; with the fully qualified hostname
            			and &lt;REALM&gt; with the Kerberos realm of the Hive service).</li>
            		</ul>
            	</p>

            	<p>
            		<b>Proprietary Impala Drivers (provided by Amazon/Hortonworks/Cloudera)</b>
            		<ul>
            			<li>AuthMech: 1</li>
            			<li>KrbHostFQDN: full qualified hostname of Hive</li>
            			<li>KrbRealm: REALM (Kerberos realm of Hive)</li>
            			<li>KrbServiceName: hive (Kerberos service name of Hive)</li>
            		</ul>
            	</p>
            </option>
            <option name="SSL/TLS">
            	The following parameters are required to use SSL/TLS. 
            	<p>
            		<b>Apache Hive Driver (default KNIME driver)</b>
            		<ul>
            			<li>ssl: true</li>
            			<li>sslTrustStore: full path of truststore</li>
            			<li>trustStorePassword: password to access the truststore</li>
            		</ul>
            	</p>

            	<p>
            		<b>Proprietary Impala Drivers (provided by Amazon/Hortonworks/Cloudera)</b>
            		<ul>
            			<li>SSL: 1</li>
            			<li>SSLTrustStore: full path of truststore</li>
            			<li>SSLTrustStorePwd: password to access the truststore</li>
            		</ul>
            	</p>
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define KNIME framework properties such as connection handling,
                advanced SQL dialect settings or logging options.
            </description>
            <option name=""></option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Input Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from database types to KNIME types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and database type will be mapped
                to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given database type will be mapped to the specified KNIME type.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Output Type Mapping">
            <description>
                This tab allows you to define rules to map from KNIME types to database types.
            </description>
            <option name="Mapping by Name">
                Columns that match the given name (or regular expression) and KNIME type will be mapped
                to the specified database type.
            </option>
            <option name="Mapping by Type">
                Columns that match the given KNIME type will be mapped to the specified database type.
            </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Database Connection">A database connection</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
