<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.12" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.12 http://knime.org/node/v2.12.xsd"
	type="Other" icon="icon.png">
	<name>JSON to Spark</name>
	<shortDescription>Creates a Spark RDD from given JSON file.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Creates a Spark RDD from given JSON file.
			
			See <a href="https://fasterxml.github.io/jackson-core/javadoc/2.4/com/fasterxml/jackson/core/JsonParser.Feature.html">Jackson JSON Parser documentation</a> for more information.
			
			<p><b>Notice:</b> This feature requires at least Spark 1.5.</p>
		</intro>
		
		<option name="Sampling ratio">
			Infer the type of a collection of JSON records in three stages:
			<ol>
				<li>Sample given amount of records and infer the type.</li>
				<li>Merge types by choosing the lowest type necessary to cover equal keys.</li>
				<li>Replace any remaining null fields with string, the top type.</li>
			</ol>
		</option>
		<option name="Primitives">Convert primitives into Strings.</option>
		<option name="Comments">Allow comments.</option>
		<option name="Fieldnames">Allow unquoted fieldnames.</option>
		<option name="Quotes">Feature that determines whether parser will allow use of single quotes (apostrophe, character '\'') for quoting Strings (names and String values).</option>
		<option name="Numerics">
			<ul>
				<li><b>Allow numeric leading zeros:</b> Feature that determines whether parser will allow JSON integral numbers to start with additional (ignorable) zeroes (like: 000001).</li>
				<li><b>Allow non numeric numbers:</b> Feature that allows parser to recognize set of "Not-a-Number" (NaN) tokens as legal floating number values (similar to how many other data formats and programming language source code allows it). Supported tokens: INF, -INF, Infinity, -Infinity and NaN.</li>
			</ul>
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Remote file connection">Spark compatible connection (HDFS, WebHDFS, HttpFS, S3, Blob Storage, ...)</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Spark context">
        	Optional Spark context. If not connected a context is created based on the settings in the Spark preferences page.
        </inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Spark data">Spark RDD</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
