<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./knoxconnection16x16.png"
		type="Source"
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>WebHDFS via KNOX Connector (Labs)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
       	Creates a WebHDFS connection using a Apache KNOX gateway in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
         <intro>
            <p>This node connects to a Hadoop Distributed File System using a Apache KNOX gateway.
            The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            the <i>files</i> of the remote file system, e.g. to read or write,
            or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths are specified with a UNIX-like syntax, /myfolder/myfile. An absolute
            for KNOX consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash ("/").</li>
                    <li>Followed by the path to the file ("myfolder/myfile" in the above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>

            <p><b>SSL:</b> This node uses the JVM SSL settings.</p>
        </intro>
        
        <tab name="Settings">
   			<option name="URL">
				Full KNOX deployment URL including cluster name e.g. https://&lt;server&gt;:8443/gateway/&lt;default&gt;/webhdfs/v1
				(replace &lt;server&gt; with the fully qualified hostname and &lt;default&gt; with you cluster/topology name).
				Protocol should be <i>https</i> and port <i>8443</i> on most deployments.
			</option>
	        <option name="Authentication">
	        	This node supports only HTTP basic authentication using workflow credentials or a given username and password.
	        </option>
		    <option name="Working directory">
		        Specify the <i>working directory</i> of the resulting file system connection, using the <b>Path syntax</b> explained above. The working
		        directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i>
		        paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. The default working directory is the root "/", under which all the
		        document libraries are located.
		    </option>
	    </tab>
	    
        <tab name="Advanced">
		    <option name="Connection timeout (seconds)">
    	        Timeout in seconds to establish a connection or 0 for an infinite timeout. 
		    </option>
		    <option name="Receive timeout (seconds)">
      	        Timeout in seconds on established connections or 0 for an infinite timeout. 
  		    </option>
		</tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
   		<outPort index="0" name="WebHDFS via KNOX File System Connection">
   			WebHDFS via KNOX File System Connection.
   		</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
