<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
		type="Source"
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Databricks File System Connector (Labs)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Connects to Databricks File System (DBFS) in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
                This node connects to the Databricks File System (DBFS) of a  Databricks deployment. The resulting
                output port allows downstream nodes to access DBFS as a file system, e.g. to read or write files and folders,
                or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for DBFS are specified with a UNIX-like syntax, for example
            <tt>/myfolder/file.csv</tt>, which is an absolute path that consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash (<tt>/</tt>).</li>
                    <li>The name of a folder (<tt>myfolder</tt>), followed by a slash.</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of a file (<tt>file.csv</tt>).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </intro>
        <tab name="Settings">
            <option name="Host">
                Full hostname (domain name) of the Databricks deployment. For example
                <tt>&lt;id&gt;.cloud.databricks.com</tt> on AWS or <tt>&lt;region&gt;.azuredatabricks.net</tt> on Azure. 
            </option>
            <option name="Port">
                Port to use. Should be 443 on most deployments.
            </option>
	        <option name="Authentication">
	            Method of authentication to use.
	            <ul>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Credentials:</b> Authenticate with the username and password of the selected credentials flow variable.
	            	</li>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Username/password:</b> Authenticate with the provided <i>Username</i> and <i>Password</i>. If entered here,
	            		the password is persistently stored (in encrypted form) in the settings of this node. Alternatively, if <i>Use credentials</i>
	            		is selected, the username and password of the selected credentials flow variable will be used for authentication.
	            	</li>
	            	<li>
	            		<b>Token:</b> Authenticate with the provided personal access <i>token</i>. If entered here,
	            		the token is persistently stored (in encrypted form) in the settings of this node. Alternatively, if <i>Use credentials</i>
	            		is selected, the password of the selected credentials flow variable will be used as the token for authentication
	            		(username of the flow variable will be ignored).
					</li>
	           	</ul>
	        </option>
            <option name="Working directory">
	            Specifies the <i>working directory</i> using the path syntax explained above. The working directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream
	            nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i> paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. If not specified, the default working directory
	            is "/".
	        </option>
	   </tab>
	   <tab name="Advanced">
	        <option name="Connection timeout">
	            Timeout in seconds to establish a connection, or 0 for an infinite timeout. 
	        </option>
	        <option name="Read timeout">
	            Timeout in seconds to read data from an established connection, or 0 for an infinite timeout.
	        </option>
        </tab>

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Databricks File System Connection">
            Databricks File System Connection
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
